

PROFILE

Business-driven General Manager with more than 15+ years of experience planning and organizing work schedules, communicating goals and objectives and complying with guidelines and procedures. Serviced-focused General Manager dedicated to delivering positive customer experiences to promote loyalty and repeat business. Orchestrates optimal resource utilization to handle expected operational needs.

SKILLS:

- -LEADERSHIP& MANAGEMENT
- -ORGANIZATION
- EXCELLENT COMMUNICATOR AND RELATIONSHIP BUILDER
- -NEGOTIATION AND PERSUASION
- -BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT
- -RISK ANALYSIS AND MANAGEMENT
- -SALE & MARKETING MANAGEMENT

CONTACT

PHONE:

+961 3 554785

LINKEDIN:

linkedin.com/in/tarek-fawal-2a001028

EMAIL:

Tarekfawal560@yahoo.com

HOBBIES

Fishing; Reading

REFERENCES: Available Upon

request.

TAREK FAWAL General Manager

EDUCATION

MINITER OF EDUCATION

- Technical Superior Managements & Organization (2019-2021)

Al Faress

- Technical Superior Information Management (2001-2003)

WORK EXPERIENCE

VICTOIR IMPORT & EXPORT General Manager 2018-Present

- Team structure, leadership, motivation and coordination in order to maximize the efficiency and effectiveness of current and future resources
- P&L responsibility
- Managing the interfaces between the Client, SPV, Building Contractor, Facilities Management Contractor and other external parties
- Business strategy and business planning in collaboration with CEO/CFO

ZRENERGY Terminal & Operations Manager 2015-2018

- Worked in matrix management environment with oversight of division level managers, operations, sales, finance, human resources, safety and compliance.
- Planned and resourced personnel and logistics for operations component exercises resulting in highly trained personnel ready to act quickly in critical roles.
- Schedules and coordinates terminal maintenance with terminal operators and third-party contractors.
- Conducts and supervises all operations in a safe and efficient manner to ensure compliance with all applicable safety, environmental and regulatory requirements.
- Responsible for development, management and execution of yearly operating budget.
- Coordinate shipments into and out of facilities tankage.
 Ensure correct product quality testing according to company procedures.

Arabian Petroleum Company Terminal & Operations Manager 2012-2015

- Coordinated meetings and logistics for national sales meetings and directed and supervised member team.
- Liaised with other directors and departmental heads to align operational priorities with total company direction.
- Facilitated business by implementing practical networking techniques.
- Oversight of all projects and activities at facility.
- Conducts and supervises all operations in a safe and efficient manner to ensure compliance with all applicable safety, environmental and regulatory requirements.

Arabian Petroleum Company Sales Supervisor 2006- 2012

- Reviewed daily metrics of account executives to evaluate strengths and weaknesses.
- Formulated tactics and strategies to target new potential customers within prioritized markets.
- Coordinated and conducted well-organized product presentations and demonstrations to potential customers at seminars and trade shows.
- Attracted new clientele and developed customer relationships by hosting product-focused events.
- Coached sales associates in product specifications, sales incentives and selling techniques, significantly increasing customer satisfaction ratings.

Sibline Cement Sales Supervisor 2003-2006

- Followed up with customers after completed sales to assess satisfaction and resolve technical or service concerns.
- Visited customer locations to evaluate requirements, demonstrate product offerings and propose strategic solutions for diverse needs.
- Established fair pricing structures and finalized contracts to complete purchase agreements with customers.
- Worked with sales team to collaboratively reach targets, consistently meeting or exceeding personal quotas.

ONE DOLLAR FMCG Company Marketing Manager 1999-2003

- Building workflows to support marketing campaigns.
- Support the marketing team by improving processes, measuring effectiveness and ensuring that important points are learnt from every campaign.
- Identifying marketing opportunities.
- Providing general administrative support across the marketing team.
- Identifying potential new affiliate partners.
- Developing marketing plans and strategies.
- Making valuable suggestions for continuous improvement and realization of targets.
- Measuring the success of marketing campaigns.